Guide to the David A. Kessler Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Interviews, 1994-2000, Series VIII
  As part of his work, Kessler recorded interviews with tobacco company executives, government officials, legal and medical scholars, and others involved with the initiative to regulate tobacco and the associated litigation against tobacco companies. The interviews provide extensive documentation of this struggle, told by major players on both sides. Researchers should consult Series IX for additional interviews.
  - Author interviews
    - Transcripts
      - Adams, David G. - Burros, Marian (Box 33, Folder 1 - 26)
      - Cady, John R.- Dutra, Edwin V. Jr. (Box 34, Folder 27 - 63)
      - Edgar, Harold - Hazard, Geoffrey C. Jr. (Box 35, Folder 64 - 91)
      - Healy, Bernadine - Kerner, Carol M. (Box 36, Folder 92 - 116)
      - Klepner, Jerry D. - Light, Gary D. and Doyle, Thomas P. (Box 37, Folder 117 - 137)
      - Liptak, Adam B. - Miller, M. Val (Box 38, Folder 138 - 159)
      - Mitchell, John - Panetta, Leon E. (Box 39, Folder 160 - 181)
      - Parrish, Stephen C. - Schori, Tom R. (Box 40, Folder 182 - 211)
      - Schultz, William B. - Thompson, Diane E. (Box 41, Folder 212 - 234)
      - Thurm, Kevin - Wykoff, Randolph F. (Box 42, Folder 235 - 258)
      - Young, Frank - Zeller, Mitchell (Box 43, Folder 259 - 268)
    - Indexed transcripts (Box 44)
    - Indexed transcripts (Box 45)
    - Floppy disks
      Closed until processed.
      - Astrue, Michael - Duggan, Juanita (Box 46)
      - Dutra, Edwin V. Jr. - Kardon, Josh (Box 47)
      - Kaufman, Nancy - Mikva, Abner (Box 48)
      - Mitchell, John - Schori, Tom R. (Box 49)
      - Schultz, William B. - Zavagno, Denise M. (Box 50)
      - Zeller, Mitchell - Zoellick, Bob [and three miscellaneous Burbach, Miriam; Cerf, Christopher; Davis, James; Gladwell, Malcolm; Johnson, Ruth; Keith, Steven; Peck, Carl; Rice, Kim; Swanson, Richard; Thompson, Diane; Thurm, Kevin] (Box 51)
    - Audio cassettes
      - Adams, David - Budich, Kevin (Box 52)
      - Budich, Kevin - Cooley, Claudia (Box 53)
      - Cooley, Claudia - Duggan, Juanita (Box 54)
      - Duggan, Juanita - Fricke, Fred (Box 55)
      - Fricke, Fred - Hickman, Harrison (Box 56)
      - Hilts, Phil - Jankowski, Joel (Box 57)
      - Janofsky, Michael - Leavitt, Joe (Box 58)
      - Lee, Phil - Light, Gary and Doyle, Tom (Box 59)
      - Light, Gary and Doyle, Tom - Mande, Jerry (Box 60)
      - Marx, Joe - Mitchell, Jack (Box 61)
      - Morris, Dick - Panetta, Leon (Box 62)
      - Panetta, Leon - Sanders, Timothy K. (Box 63)
      - Sanders, Timothy K. - Slade, John (Box 64)
      - Slade, John - Taylor, John (Box 65)
      - Taylor, John - Wilkenfeld, Judith (Box 66)
      - Wilkenfeld, Judith - Zeller, Mitchell (Box 67)
      - Zeller, Mitchell - Zoellick, Robert (Box 68)
  - Miscellaneous interviews
    - Transcripts [Brzeczek, Richard - Turano, Louis] (Box 69, Folder 269 - 297)
    - Disks [Cornejo, Gerardo - Ruland, Wendy] (Box 70)
    - Audio cassettes
      - Cornejo, Gerado - Kessler, David and Stephen Whitlock (Box 71)
      - Magrain, Mary - Ruland, Wendy (Box 72)
- Informant Files, 1961-1998, undated; Series IX
  Arrangement
  The series is arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  The series consists of interview transcripts, copies of documents, and research notes pertaining to confidential informants.
  As part of his work, Kessler recorded interviews with tobacco company executives, government officials, legal and medical scholars, and others involved with the initiative to regulate tobacco and the associated litigation against tobacco companies. The interviews provide extensive documentation of this struggle, told by major players on both sides. Researchers should consult Series VIII for additional interviews.
  - Guide, 1997 (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - Interview list, 1994-1995 (Box 73, Folder 2)
  - Abood, Leo, 1994 October 3 (Box 73, Folder 3)
  - AD Little, 1989 (Box 73, Folder 4)
  - Anonymous, 1994 March 4 (Box 73, Folder 5)
  - "Bama", Undated (Box 73, Folder 6)
  - "Beach", 1992-1995 (Box 73, Folder 7-8)
  - Belcher, Gary, 1994 December 15 (Box 73, Folder 9)
  - "Bellomy", 1994 October 5-November 8 (Box 73, Folder 10)
  - "Bio", 1994 June 8 (Box 73, Folder 11)
  - "Bio II", 1995 December 21 (Box 73, Folder 12)
  - "Bio-Bio", 1994 August 23 (Box 73, Folder 13)
  - "Bob", 1994 March (Box 73, Folder 14)
  - "Book", 1994 July 14-20 (Box 73, Folder 15)
  - Bravo, 1994 May 25 (Box 73, Folder 16)
  - "Brew", 1994 September 19 (Box 73, Folder 17)
  - Brown and Williamson, 1994 June 17 (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - "Bud", Undated (Box 74, Folder 2)
  - "Cap", 1995 February 23 (Box 74, Folder 3)
  - "Carp", 1995 March 30 (Box 74, Folder 4)
  - Chaplin
    - Handwritten notes, 1994 June 10 (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - Day 1 transcription, 1994 June 10 (Box 74, Folder 6)
  - "CI", 1994 March 14 (Box 74, Folder 7)
  - "Cigarette" (John DeNoble), 1994-1998 (Box 74, Folder 8)
  - "Cigarette, Jr." (Paul Mele), 1994 March 18 (Box 74, Folder 9)
  - "Computer", 1995 June 13 (Box 74, Folder 10)
  - "CON", 1994 August 18 (Box 74, Folder 11)
  - "Crop", 1994 May 25 (Box 74, Folder 12)
  - "Curly", 1995 June 29 (Box 74, Folder 13)
  - "DNAP", 1994 May 3-June 10 (Box 74, Folder 14-15)
  - "Deep Cough", 1992-1998 (Box 75, Folder 1-3)
  - DiMarco, 1992 October 18, undated (Box 75, Folder 4)
  - "DOC", 1993-1995 (Box 75, Folder 5-6)
  - "Durham", 1987-1995, undated (Box 75, Folder 7)
  - Dunn, William, 1961, 1974, 1994, undated (Box 75, Folder 8-9)
  - Farmer, 1994 June 14-August 26 (Box 75, Folder 10-11)
  - Former Philip Morris employee from Birmingham, Undated (Box 75, Folder 12)
  - Garcia, 1994 August 29-30 (Box 76, Folder 1)
  - Gilbert, 1994 (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - Gold, 1995 February 22-28 (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - Griffith, 1994 June 1 (Box 76, Folder 4)
  - Heep, Hatsy, 1996 April 5 (Box 76, Folder 5)
  - "Hershey", 1994 October 20 (Box 76, Folder 6)
  - "Howard", 1996 February 14, April 16 (Box 76, Folder 7)
  - Ikeda, Bob, 1995 April 27 (Box 76, Folder 8)
  - Informant call, 1994 August 9 (Box 76, Folder 9)
  - Informants - Nicotine plasma levels, what FDA was told about plasma levels, Undated (Box 76, Folder 10)
  - "Interior", Undated (Box 76, Folder 11)
  - Investigative informant file, 1994 May 10, undated (Box 76, Folder 12)
  - "John" -- product developer, 1994 April 28 (Box 76, Folder 13)
  - Kreisher, John, 1995 October 19, 25, undated (Box 76, Folder 14)
  - Lawson, Jeffrey, Undated (Box 76, Folder 15)
  - "Legit", 1994 December 19 (Box 76, Folder 16)
  - Macon, 1989-1994, undated (Box 77, Folder 1-4)
  - Mold, James, Dr. -- L&M, 1988, undated (Box 77, Folder 5)
  - Morris, 1996 February 12, undated (Box 77, Folder 6)
  - Mueller, Mr., 1994 November 9 (Box 77, Folder 7)
  - "Murphy", 1994 December 7 (Box 77, Folder 8)
  - "Nic", 1994 August 17 (Box 77, Folder 9)
  - Notes, 1994 February 28-1995 February 17 (Box 77, Folder 10-12)
  - "Nurse", 1994 November 30 (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - "Nutmeg", Undated (Box 78, Folder 2)
  - "Oak", 1995 January 3 (Box 78, Folder 3)
  - "Ohio", 1994 June 24-August 16 (Box 78, Folder 4)
  - "Package", 1995 June 1 (Box 78, Folder 5)
  - "Painter", 1995 June 1 (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - "Phil"
    - 1994 April 29 (Box 78, Folder 7)
    - 1994 May 16 (Box 78, Folder 8)
    - 1995 May 4 (Box 78, Folder 9)
    - 1996 February 21 (Box 78, Folder 10)
  - "Philip", 1994 March-Jun, 1996 Feb, undated (Box 79, Folder 1-3)
  - Philip Morris employee statement, Undated (Box 79, Folder 4)
  - "Production", 1994 March 13-April 28 (Box 79, Folder 5)
  - "Radio", 1994 May 18 (Box 79, Folder 6)
  - "Recon", 1994 June 6-July 7, undated (Box 79, Folder 7-8)
  - "Research"
    - Handwritten notes, 1994 May 13 (Box 79, Folder 9)
    - Part 1 transcript, 1994 May 13 (Box 79, Folder 10)
    - Part 2 transcript, 1994 May 17 (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - Day 3, 1994 May 24 (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - Day 4, 1994 June 1 (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - Day 5, 1994 June 9 (Box 80, Folder 4)
  - RJR informants: "Tack," "Carp," "Tiger", 1994 August 9, 1995 January 19, October 15 (Box 80, Folder 5)
  - Rowe, 1994 May 10 (Box 80, Folder 6)
  - "Storry", 1994 October 27 (Box 80, Folder 7)
  - "Sugar", 1994 July 14 (Box 80, Folder 8)
  - "Tack", 1995 October 26 (Box 80, Folder 9)
  - "Tiger", 1994 November 29 (Box 81, Folder 1)
  - "Tiger" premiere, 1994-1996 (Box 81, Folder 2)
  - Tobacco interviews/confidential source related, 1994 March 3-7, undated (Box 81, Folder 3)
  - Vessel, 1994 October 13 (Box 81, Folder 4)
  - Virginia, 1991-1992, undated (Box 81, Folder 5)
  - "Virginia" -- Tom Doyle, Gary Light notes, 1994 January 20 (Box 81, Folder 6)
  - Wernsman, 1994 March 23 (Box 81, Folder 7)
  - Yu, 1994 July 11, undated (Box 81, Folder 8)